<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
<a rel="me" href="https://fosstodon.org/@koreymoffett"></a>
<channel>
<title>Korey's Blog</title>
<description>Updates from Korey.</description>
<language>en-us</language>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml</link>
<atom:link href="https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<image>
<title>Korey's Blog</title>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/rss.xml</link>
</image>

<item>
<title>Switching to Emacs</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/switching-to-emacs</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/switching-to-emacs</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Doom-Emacs</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I first started coding about 2 years ago off and on as nothing serious, just as a way to tinker about with my computer when I was at home, but as I started to get deeper and deeper into the rabbit hole that is coding I started to look for
                a serious text editor. When I first started I was using a program called Atom to edit my code(you may have heard of it, the text editor made by github).
                <br> I looked online and saw many people used Atom and that Github was the creater of it so it seemed like a no-brainer. Since then however I have tried nearly every editor under the sun, I tried Atom, Sublime Text, VSCode(Still use some),
                and Vim and I must say most of them were a complete let down.
                <br> For example, When I used Sublime i was always so annoyed by it's keybinding and it's just rather dull design. With Atom, it was great for awhile until it started really slowing down do to the number of add-ons I had and needed for
                the projects I was working on. For Vim and VSCode, These two actually haven't let me down they have been amazing since the day I started using them, but I think it's time to give Emacs a fair chance.
                <br> I always hated on Emacs, saying 'This program has the most idiotic key binds/key-chords', then i found Doom-Emacs(Thanks DistroTube). I have only been using Doom-Emacs for about two hours and I can whole heartly say I love it. Because
                it's Vim, VSCode and Emacs all smashed into one package.
                <br> If you have been looking for a terminal based or GUI text editor that's pretty lightweight but still has all the features you will ever need, I highly recommend Doom-Emacs.

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Happy Holidays</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/happy-holidays</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/happy-holidays</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Happy Holidays</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">It's Christmas today! Merry Christmas and Happy Holidays to everyone.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>I'll never buy a Mac</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/ill-never-buy-mac</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/ill-never-buy-mac</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Never again</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I don't have some horror story of my keyboard breaking or my screen just dying on me, in fact my macbook has held up pretty good. But I have since learned about Linux and after installing Linux on my desktop I see absolutly no reason for Apple
                to even make computers at all to be honestly(Other than to make money but that's obvious.).
                <br> Macs try to fill this really weird area of computing that I just don't see a purpose for. For anything you need to do you can use Linux or Windows and they will do the job better in many cases (other than make apps for iphone and
                mac)
                <br>
                <br> Macs are just super expensive computers with lowend specs, and about 80% of the price you paid for that mac is so you can have that Apple logo on the back.
                <br> I'm not someone who buys a new laptop every year in fact I wait until the laptop has more than one issue to buy a new one in most cases, but I can say with 100% certainty that I will never buy another apple computer rather it be a
                laptop or a desktop mac ever again.
                <br>
                <br> Linux is my prefered OS to compute on.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Why use FOSS?</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/foss</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/foss</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Why should you care?</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">I guess first I should start of by explaining what FOSS is, FOSS is Free and Open Source Software.
                <br> For a program or software to be consitered free(as in freedom, has nothing to do with price.) it first has to meet the four essential freedoms.
                <br>
                <br>
                <ul>
                    <li>Freedom 0: The freedom to run the program as you wish, for any purpose.<li>
                        <li>Freedom 1: The freedom to study how the program works, and change it so it does your computing as you wish.</li>
                        <li>Freedom 2: The freedom to redistribute copies so you can help others.</li>
                        <li>Freedoom 3: The freedom to distribute copies of your modified verison to others. By doing this you can give the whole community a chance to benefit from your changes. Access to the source code is a necessity.</li>
                </ul>
                <br>
                <br>
                Now, to answer the question, "Why should you care about FOSS?"<br>
                You should truly care about FOSS because unlike most software/programs, FOSS won't collect data about you to sell to the highest bidder, but it also gives you the freedom to change the things you don't like about the program or to change the things you need to change to be able to use the program. For example lets say there is a program that someone needs to use but they can't read the font size due to a vision impairment, Well with FOSS they could easily change the font size because they have access to the source code. Not only that but you can also have the peace of mind that the program isn't sending your information to people or companies who have no real reason to see your information.
                <br>
                <br>
                Supporting FOSS is supporting Freedom!
                <br>
                <hr>
                Please consider donating your time or donating financially to these organizations to help push FOSS forward:
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://www.fsf.org/">Free Software Foundation<a>
                    <br>
                    <a href="https://www.eff.org/">Electronic Frontier Foundation<a>
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Distro hopping is pointless</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/distro-hopping</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/distro-hopping</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">We all do it but it's dumb</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                In the Linux world there is a term you will hear thrown around a lot and that "Distro hop" or "Distro hopping", as the name suggests this is when someone installs distribution after distibution expecting to find that perfect one.
                <br>
                Distro hopping just out of curiosity isn't bad in my personaly opinion, but I think constantly wiping your hard drive(ssd in most cases these days) is pointless.
                <br>
                Finding that magic linux distro isn't going to happen, none of them are perfect and anything you don't like about the distro you are currently running(or thinking about running) is easily changable.
                The only real reason I can see for distro hopping is say for example you are running ubuntu and you want something more minimal you could install something like Debian or Arch other than that there isn't much purpose in it.
                <br>
                <br>
                I myself have been that new to linux user who want to try the newest shiny thing he sees but it really is a massive waste of time, energy and can be damaging to your workflow as well.
                <br>
                <br>
                I recently made the switch to base debian as I wanted a more minimal system and so far I have had zero issues. Debian is rock solid and thats why I love it.
                Sure it may not have the lastest packages, but you when you install a package you can know for a fact it will work, unlike with arch.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Stop Using Twitter!</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/stop-using-twitter</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/stop-using-twitter</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">and other freedom hating platforms.</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                As you my know recently platforms like Twitter, Facebook, Snapchat and many others have been recently banning and removing anyone they disagree with rather it's a political belief or
                your favorite breakfast cereal Big Tech has shown that it can defy the laws and do what it wants.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you are looking for some alternatives to those freedom hating platforms here are a few.
                <br>
                <br>
                <ul>
                    <li><a href="joinmastodon.org">Mastodon</a></li> - Twitter like but completly federated. I personaly am on the fosstodon instance.
                    <li><a href="lbry.tv">LBRY</a>/<a href="odysee.com">Odysee</a></li> - This can replace Youtube and even has a neat crypto system to tip the creators, both of these are the same things they just have diffrent UI
                    <li><a href="signal.org">Signal</a></li> - This isn't a free and open source application but if you are still using whatsapp or any other facebook trash this is a good replacemant and lets you encrypt your messages.
                </ul>
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>What is Mastodon</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 19:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">the elephant is better than the bird.</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                If you read <a href="stop-using-twitter">Stop Using Twitter!</a> you my recall that I mentioned something called Mastodon
                Mastodon is a social site that allows users to set up instances and microblog comparable to Twitter.
                However the benifits to Mastodon far outweigh anything twitter has to offer.
                <br>
                Mastodon is a federated social site meaning there is no central rule book or agenda being followed.
                <br>
                The users will join an instance that best suits there intrests or there intrest leading to communities being built around a common intrest.
                You may think it's a bad thing that there are no central rules to the site but let me explain, each instance has it's own rules.
                <br>
                For example some instances may not allow users to use foul language and some may fully allow it.
                <br>
                <br>
                The beauty of a site like Mastodon is that even if your instance kicks you, you can still go join another instance with the same account.
                <br>
                If you were on mstdon.social and they decided they don't like what you are posting or maybe you broke the rules and kick you, you could go join fosstodon.org (which is the instance im in).
                As you can see just from the very few point I actully talked about mastodon does still have a way of regulating itself and dealing with the trolls.
                <br>
                <br>
                <hr>
                If you are intrested in joining up on mastodon and have a love for FOSS(Free and Open Source Software)
                I would highly recommend joining <a href="https://fosstodon.org">Fosstodon</a> I have been here for a few months now and I have had a very good time.
                <br>
                It's actually like a little community of some pretty cool people.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you aren't into FOSS but still want to join mastodon i recommend going to <a href="https://instances.social">Matodon Instances</a> here you will find tons of other instances that may suit you better.
                    <br>
                    I hope to see many new toots on mastodon :)  (post on mastodon are called toots i'm not weird or something lol)

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Noob Distros</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mastodon</link>
<pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2021 17:24:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">This first step into the world of GNU/Linux</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                Before i begin i guess i should say this post is mostly for new to linux users, however you are more than welcome to keep reading if you are a pro as well :)
                <br>
                If you are new to linux or maybe you are looking to jump into linux i would highly recommend using Pop! OS, Linux Mint or maybe Manjaro and ill tell you why.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://pop.system76.com"/>Pop! OS</a> is actually the first distro i ever installed and i never had any issues with it, It also has some pretty good defaults
                as well as works pretty well "out of the box" for you gamers.
                <br>
                Although i'm no longer a fan of GNOME the desktop enviornment is very well polished and perfect for the new user to really get a little more comfortable with a linux system.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://linuxmint.com"/>Linux Mint</a> is another very popular and well regarded distro for many reasons.
                <br>
                It has a very familiar feel to Windows so it's perfect for those of you moving from Windows as well as has a very help full community, so if you have any issues feel free to ask the
                linux mint community.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://manjaro.org"/>Manjaro</a> is a good distro if you are wanting to jump into the arch side of things without the hassle of installing main line arch, and thats honestly the thing manjaro is most known for,
                it's user friendly nature while still letting you harness the power of arch. However i must say manjaro is a much less forgiving system if you make changes your shouldn't have more install a bad package.
                <br>
                <br>
                At the end of the day though it's important to remember that distro doesn't matter, once you get familiar with the differences between debian and arch (the two main distros)
                linux is linux is linux.
                <br>
                I hope to see you noobies in the linux communities asking questions :).
                <br>
                <br>
                oh, i use debian btw
            </p>

]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Software I Use</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/software-used</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/software-used</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:45:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">My favorites so far</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                As you can tell my the title of this post I wanted to make a quick little post sharing the software/programs
                I use on a daily basis.
                <br>
                <br>
                My distro of choice is GNU/Linux Debian (Buster).
                <br>
                I really like debian for many reasons but the main reason is its stability, you don't have to worry about updating and your system braking as debian has many layers of production to ensure that won't happen.
                <br>
                Also I really like the logo lol(not a main reason but thought I would throw that in).
                <br>
                <br>
                The window manager I've been using for some time now is Spectrwm, I really like the simplicity.
                <br>
                It's config file is beyond easy to customize and the baked in statusbar is more than enough for my needs.
                <br>
                <br>
                Now on to text editors... here is where everyone pulls out their swords and prepares to battle.
                <br>
                My text editor of choice is both Vim and Emacs, let me explain lol. For bigger projects such as this website or any other projects I will be spending time input
                I use Emacs but not base emacs I actually use a distro of Emacs called Doom-Emacs. And as far as Vim I mostly use it for those quick edits to a file say maybe my .zshrc.
                <br>
                <br>
                My terminal as of now is Kitty but honestly I like Alacritty just as much, I can pretty much any terminal emulator.
                <br>
                <br>
                My web browser of choice is Brave at the moment but I'm not quite sure if i'll be sticking with it yet.
                <br>
                <br>
                And this one I just kinda threw into the list last minute but for a graphical file manager i use pcmanfm, because it is dead simple.


            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Tusky is an amazing mobile app</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/tusky</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/tusky</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 22:10:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[

<h1 class="subtitle">Mastodon Client</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                I have been using <a href="https://tusky.app/">Tusky</a> now for around 3 months and I have nothing but the best to say about it.
                <br>
                <br>
                I have tried other mastodon clients before and all of them work yes, but none of them have the same level of polish as Tusky.
                <br>
                I started using Tusky right after I completly got rid of my Twitter account and even the twitter app doesn't come close to the the same clean and polished design of Tusky.
                <br>
                The best part about Tusky is that it is completly free and open source software. I think it's only avaliable on Android devices through.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you are intrested in giving it a try I recommend downloading with F-droid instead of Google Play.(Google is the devil Fdroid is the bringer of all things good...oh and it's FOSS so its a no brainer for me).
                <br>
                <br>
                <h1 class="subtitle">Life update</h1>
                <br>
                I will be moving pretty soon and i'm not sure about the internet situation at the new place, so that being said im not sure when my next blog post will be. (I will be back ASAP).
                <br>
                Take care everyone. :)
            </p>

]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>I'm back</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/back</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/back</link>
<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 07:46:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
<![CDATA[

<h1 class="subtitle">The return of Me Myself and I</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                Hello everyone, if you read my last blog post I said that I would be moving and I wasn't sure about the internet situation at the new house, well it turns out that
                we actually can't get an actual ISP so we have to use mobile hotspots for all things internet.
                <br>
                As bad as that might sound it's actually been pretty simple and the connection has been pretty stable.
                <br>
                <br>
                Also, I started learning C++, I was learning C but from what I can see C++ is just C with more features and by learning C++ i'm pretty much learning C.
                <br>
                <br>
                That's it.. thats my little update
            </p>

]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>One week on Solus</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/solus</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/solus</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 20:54:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">I distro hopped after telling you not to hehe</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              First let me explain why I made the switch in the first place.
              <br>
              About a week ago I made the bright decision(This is sarcasm im just not good at it) to switch over to Debian testing from Debian stable and to make a long story short it didn't go well.
              <br>
              Now at this point a person who had good system admin skills and or half a brain in there head would be like "Good thing I make back ups!", this person is not me lol.
              <br>
              <br>
              So i decided to give solus a try as i've always thought solus was pretty cool from everything i read and had seen on the distribution.
              <br>
              Fast forward a week and these are my thoughts.
              <br>
              Solus is the perfect example of easy to install, a beautiful user interface and mostly sane pre-installed software(i say mostly because it is a bit heavy out of the box)
              <br>
              I am still currently blown away by how beautiful and easy to use the Budgie desktop evironment really is, it has become my favorite desktop enviornment.
              And i dont forsee myself moving away from solus as package avaliblity hasn't been an issue for me.
              <br>
              The worst things about this distro for me were getting my brain to remember eopkg rather than apt or pacman or something and the pre-installed software that i mentioned previously.
              <br>
              <br>
              <h1 class "subtitle">State of the blog/Life Update</h1>
              <br>
              Recently I had my website Brave verified as currently i do not have a job and the search for one doesn't seem to be getting any better
              <br>
              I will never lock anything i make behind a pay wall just letting everyone know why i verified my website as I try to be as trasparent as possible.
              <br>
              If you only view this in an RSS reader than you can disregard this.
              <br>
              <br>
              :)
            </p>



]]>
</description>
</item>



<item>
<title>Shouting out bloggers</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/shoutout</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/shoutout</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 19:40:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">Give these blogs a look</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              I couldn't think of a topic to write about today that I thought anyone else would actually want to take the time to read so i decided why not make a blog post shouting out other bloggers.
              Seems like a good idea to me.
              <br>
              <br>
              (This list has no ordered and all bloggers can be found on fosstodon)<!--LINK FOSSTODON-->
              <br>
              <a href="https://fosstodon.org/web/accounts/210111">Joel Cherono</a> is a blogger who post very regularly on topic generally focused on technology to some degree but isn't afraid to go on a rant or two about other things.
              <br>
              <br>
              <a href="https://joelchrono12.ml/blog/">Blog</a>
              <br>
              <a href="https://joelchrono12.ml/feed.xml">RSS Feed</a>
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://fosstodon.org/web/accounts/1">Kev Quirk</a> is another blogger with a focus mostly on technology but also sprinkles in a little bit about blogging itself.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://kevq.uk/blog/">Blog</a>
                <br>
                <a href="https://kevq.uk/feed/">Rss Feed</a>
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://fosstodon.org/web/accounts/32">Mike Stone</a>, like the previous bloggers this blogger also has a focus on technology, if you like well written posts defiantly give this one a look.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://mikestone.me/blog/">Blog</a>
                <br>
                I couldn't find an RSS Feed for this blogger but I will be sure to update this if I do.
                <br>
                <br>
                <br>
                There you go, those are 3 bloggers that I think deserve your attention. Also make sure you follow them on fosstodon, I linked each of there accounts in this post so it would be easy for you.
                <br>
                <br>
                Thank you for reading :)

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Fond memories of Pokemon</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/pokemon</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/pokemon</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 07:51:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[

<h1 class="subtitle">Gotta catch 'em all'</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              I was scrolling through the eshop on my nintendo switch and stumbled across Pokemon Sword and Shield, the two newest games in the Pokemon series or saga if you will. Seeing the cover art and the giant yellow letters spelling out Pokemon really brought back memories of the series from my childhood.
              I remember the first pokemon game I ever played seriously was Pokemon emerald, It was made for the gameboy advanced and i remember playing that game for hours and hours everyday. On the bus ride to school, at lunch time in school and even when i got home, I guess you could say I was addicted. Then out of nowhere i just kinda stopped playing it, stop playing pokemon at all.
              <br>
              I didn't move on to a newer game until I got my first nintendo DS, my brother already had a pokemon game and i remember watching him play it and it really brought that love for pokemon back out so for my birthday i asked my grandmother if she could buy me Pokemon Platinum (which was the newest at the time) and she did but she also bought me Pokemon Diamond as well. I was beyond excited when I unwrapped those gifts.
              <br>
              <br>
              Later that day the addiction to Pokemon was back, yes you can relapse on Pokemon because i did it lol.
              My brother and I would say up for over 24 hours even on school nights helping each other get pokemon we wanted by trading and showing each other little tricks to be more efficient with our playthrough of the game, and of course we spent many hours trying to best each other in battles as well (You know its kinda a rules brothers have to fight). I restarted that game so many times i couldn't even keep up with how many times i had beaten the game.
              <br>
              <br>
              I am now buying the newest pokemon game many years later, as im writing this that game is installing and I couldn't be more excited. If pokemon even held a percentage of the same gameplay i remember i am sure i will love it.
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>First impressions pokemon</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/first-impressions-pokemon-shield</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/first-impressions-pokemon-shield</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 02:22:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">5 hours in and still going?</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              If you read my blog post yesterday titled <a href="/blog/pokemon">Fond memories of Pokemon</a> you will remember I said I was buying the my first Pokemon game since my childhood to see if I could find that same love for Pokemon that I once had.
              <br>
              This is my thought on the game 5 hours in...
              <br>
              <br>
              If you are looking for the short anwser yes, I do like it. But there are also many things about it that either A I flat out don't like or B I wish they just wouldn't have messed with.
              <br>
              If you have played any Pokemon games before you know the whole plot of the game is you are going around the region in the game trying to catch all the pokemon and collect all the gym badges, and that part of the game still hold true, Pokemon found it's formula many years ago and it works so I am happy to see that wasn't altered.
              <br>
              However they did add quite a few new things as I expected they would. One of the main thing I actually don't like about the game is... wait for it... the new generation of pokemon, maybe it's just me wanting the same Pokemon I grew up with but these new pokemon have almost no charm to them at all. Many of them are completly forgetable or just flat out odd.
              The other big thing I don't like about this game is the addition of Dynamax, Dynamax is the new hype in the Pokemon world and if you don't know what it is, well it's probably for the better.
              Dynamaxing your Pokemon is done my a bracelet that can store some sort of special electrical charge that allows you to power up your Pokemon into these super behemoths... so yes you can have a Pikachu the size of or larger than buildings. This gripe with the game i'm almost sure is me wanting to play some good old fashion Pokemon.
              <br>
              <br>
              The core game play however like I stated previously has remaind mostly unalted which does actually still allow me to enjoy the game. I'm 5 hours in and I've already collected one badge.
              <br>
              Will I catch them all? Will I collect all the badges? Will I become the best like no one ever was?
              <br>
              <br>
              :) Thanks for reading

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Favorite Mobile Apps</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mobile-apps</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/mobile-apps</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 01:05:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[

<h1 class="subtitle">Personal tracking device software</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                Every app on this list is available on Android through the <a href="https://f-droid.org">F-droid</a> store.
                <br>
                <br>
                First on the list is <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.keylesspalace.tusky/">Tusky</a> the mobile <a href="https://joinmastodon.org">Mastodon</a> client. If you use Mastodon and you are looking for a mobile client they don't get any better than this.
                <br>
                <br>
                Next we have <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.nononsenseapps.feeder/"> Feeder</a> an RSS reader, this app is where I personally read a good 80% of all the blogs and news I read, it's fantastic.
                <br>
                <br>
                <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/ml.docilealligator.infinityforreddit/"> Infinity for Reddit</a> is a wonderful and beautiful reddit client that has loads of customization. You could theme this app to match that love for the Nord theme or maybe Gruvbox. It's a must have for all you redditors.
                <br>
                <br>
                What's the weather going to be like tomorrow? <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/com.mbestavros.geometricweather/">Geometric Weather</a> has the latest on that and anything else you want to know weather related, it's beautiful and simple to read. It just works and looks beautiful doing it.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you are like me you love FOSS and one of the things that's hardest to break from is YouTube, what's the alternative you ask? <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/io.lbry.browser/">LBRY F-Droid</a> is the best thing we have currently to something like youtube but don't let that make you think it's not amazing because it truly is. You can get paid simply to watch videos in the crypto currency LBC and you can be greedy and hold it all for yourself or the better option use it to support the creators that bring your entertainment or information.
                <br>
                <br>
                 EDIT: Thank you to <a href="https://fosstodon.org/web/accounts/323554">Reaper</a> (give this guy a follow over on mastodon, he makes all kinds of super cool projects) for reminding me about an app that I actually originally intended to add to the list but as I was typing this blog I completly forgot at some point along the way. That app is <a href="https://f-droid.org/en/packages/org.schabi.newpipe/">NewPipe</a>, this app allows you to interact with YouTube while not actually using googles app (Which is always a plus if you love FOSS).
                <br>
                <br>
                Please consider supporting these apps and fdroid rather that be financially or through your time, also a giant thank you to the developers of these apps and everyone who has already contributed.
            </p>

]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Thoughts on Javascript</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/thouhgts-on-js</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/thouhgts-on-js</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 08:18:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">The Good the Bad and the Slow</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              JavaScript, You either love it or you hate it... well actually that's not true. See I don't believe JavaScript is inherently bad, in fact if used correctly I't allows for some very useful and even just plain cool things to be anchived from the web browser.
              <br>
              Don't get me wrong I still thing JavaScript shouldn't be used nearly as much as it is. For example, If you are just trying to have a sentence display on your website their is absolutly no reason to do that with JavaScript. HTML and CSS should still be the core of all websites, JavaScript is a little spice you throw in to give a little pizzaz or for a cool animation here and there.
              <br>
              When JavaScript is used to the point that the entire site is just a giant script or a million little scripts is where I see a huge issue with it, It's just slow and pointless at that point really.
              <br>
              <br>
              This is a super short blog but I just really wanted to get my thoughts out on it and also announce that I'm going to be learning JavaScript(I know sue me right lol) as I would like to get more into web development.
              <br>
              <br>
              I'm actually pretty curious of what you guys think.
              <br>
              Is JavaScript the Devil or not so bad?
              <br>
              Let me know in the comments :)

            </p>


]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Free Software Rant</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/free-software-rant</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/free-software-rant</link>
<pubDate>Sat, 27 Mar 2021 08:28:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[

<h1 class="subtitle">The "I have nothing to hide" argument</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              I have spoken to many people who don't know about the free software movement and I have done the best that I can to explain the pros to free software and why they should to the best of their ablity replace non-free software in their lives.
              <br>
              But of course we all know what comes next, "Oh, I'm not really worried about that I have nothing to hide." Now this argument is dumb to many degrees but I will explain the lack of thinking in this argument.
              <br>
              <br>
              These people who say "I have nothing to hide" do in fact all have something to hide, actually everyone on the planet has something to hide that doesn't mean what you are hiding is illegal and it doesn't mean you are a bad person either necessarily, it could be something as simple as a password you don't want people having access to but we all have something to hide.
              <br>
              <br>
              I would assume that most of these people don't let just anyone walk into their homes at any given time and look through their things so why would they let people and or companies do that very thing to their digital life?
              <br>
              Would these people also not make police get a warrent to search their house?
              <br>
              <br>
              Of course the answer to these questions is no they wouldn't let any of that slide. So are these people detaching themselves from their online life or are they actually so oblivious to whats going on and they don't belive they have anything to worry about?
              <br>
              Surely they know about Edward Snowden and the other whistle blowers so my only conclusion is willfull ignorance.
              <br>
              <br>
              Speaking of Edward Snowden here is a quote from him that kinda sums up this whole thing.
              <br>
              <br>
              Arguing that you don't care about the right to privacy because you have nothing to hide is no different than saying you don't care about free speech because you have nothing to say. Nobody needs to justify why they 'need' a right. The burden of justification falls on the one seeking to infringe upon the right. You can't give away the rights of others because they're not useful to you. More simply, the majority cannot vote away the natural rights of the minority. -- Edward Snowden
              <br>
              <br>
              This was kinda a rant just questioning the people who say "I have nothing to hide" I would love to see what you guys think about this, Feel free to leave a comment :)

            </p>


]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Cancle Culture</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/cancle-culture</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/cancle-culture</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 08:50:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[

  <h1 class="subtitle">I don't like what you said so *poof* you are gone</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                On the off chance that you haven't heard the term Cancle Culture before I wil give you the definition.
                <br>
                <br> Cancle Culture refers to the popular practice of with drawing support for (canceling) public figures and companies after they have done or said something objectionable or offensive. Cancle culture is generally discussed as being performed
                on social media in the form of group shaming.
                <br>
                <a href="https://www.dictionary.com/e/pop-culture/cancel-culture/">Source</a>

                <br>
                <br> Many people seem to not have any issue with this, but I have a huge issue with this practice.
                <br> Because the people doing this cancleing are inconsistance, they will tell in one moment to be yourself and then in the next moment you are being canclled because they don't like who you are.
                <br> This goes much further than personal traits as well, they can cancle you for anything they deem 'wrong' rather that be your political views, religion, race or anything else.
                <br>
                <br> Do you know why so many people like me think this practice is bad and dangerous, it's because we have looked at history and seen the lynch mobs and the riots and killing of people who were 'witches' the cancling doesn't stop until
                it goes way overboard and results in the loss of lives and destruction of those they deem bad.
                <br> As long as we as people in society (insert we live in a society meme) allow the bully tactics to work they will keep doing it.
                <br> So stand strong and don't bow down to the mob.
                <br> They are in a mob because they are weak on their own.
                <br>
                <br> My advise to anyone who finds themselve in this situation.
                <br> 1.) Don't apologize to the mob, if you say sorry you are admitting that you did something wrong and that you deserve the treatment.
                <br> 2.) Ignore them to the best of your ablility, They will harass you until you break if you let them.
                <br> 3.) Keep in mind you aren't cancled unless you allow yourself to be, Their whole game is a bully tactic, don't allow it to be your end.
            </p>



]]>
</description>
</item>


<item>
<title>My Love for Emacs</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/my-love-for-emacs</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/my-love-for-emacs</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 10:33:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">How Emacs conquered my computer</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                My first blog post I ever made was about Doom Emacs and here we are again at last.
                <br>
                I would like to start of by saying I never stopped using Doom Emacs since the first post I've just actually started looking further into Emacs and playing around with stuff more.
                If you are wondering why I use Doom Emacs and not just vanilla Emacs it's because I NEED the Vim bindings or as Emacs folk call it Evil Mode.
                <br>
                At first Doom Emacs was a text editor for me and that was all, never messed with Org Mode or Magit or anything. Coming from Vim thats all I had ever known and I always heard that Emacs was a text editor, which isn't completely wrong but is an understatement for sure.
                <br>
                <br>
                If you are following me on Mastodon (and if you aren't and you are view from my website click the blue icon at the top and fix that lol) you would have noticed that I've been posting about Emacs quite a lot in the past two days or so and that's because I have really grasped the power of Org Mode.
                <br>
                <br>
                Org Mode is sooooooo much more than just a markdown language, In Org Mode you can even code, yes you can code in Org, the org-bable-tangle package allows you to write config files or even straight up program in a .org file and have it's code blocks sent to the original config file.
                For anyone who hasn't used Org Mode it's really hard to actually understand why people would love it so much, I even thought Org Mode was just some markdown language that people were pushing to get more people using Emacs but after using it you will fully understand.
                <br>
                <br>
                Magit is the other feature in Emacs that I absolutely love, I can stage my files before I commit or push them, the commit option allows you to make all files have the same commit message(which I like) and it's simply a M-x magit-push away from being pushed to your git repo.
                <br>
                I absolutely love Magit and Org Mode and I don't see myself ever leaving Emacs because those two features are just killer when it comes to productivity.
                <br>
                <br>
                I don't promise Emacs will be perfect for you, in fact if you are a vim user because you like the UNIX philosophy of 'Do one thing and do it well' you probably won't like Emacs as its super extensible to the point of being basically it's own operating system.
                <br>
                <br>
                For me, Emacs is my editor, file manager, and so much more.
            </p>

]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hacking on Emacs</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/hacking-on-emacs</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/hacking-on-emacs</link>
<pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 10:33:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">Elisp is weird</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                My last post <a href="blog/my-love-for-emacs">My Love for Emacs</a> I talked about how I have seriously started to use Emacs and was looking more into making Emacs the tool I want it to be.
                <br>
                I've began doing that and I'm actually very suprised with how easy it is. From the first time I heard of Emacs about 3ish years ago or so I always thought Emacs was this sort of elite program that required serious programming skills.
                <br>
                <br>
                Well, I can now say that it's not that at all. It's for anyone who enjoys hacking on something and making something theirs, keybinding, setting packages to run on default and everything else that goes into hacking on Emacs. The only thing that may trip people up is the Elisp language used to to modify or extend Emacs.
                <br>
                <br>
                For example, this is a snippet of elisp code form my config.el.
                <br>
                <br>
                <div class="notification">
                    (use-package org-bullets<br>
                    :ensure t<br>
                    :config<br>
                    (add-hook 'org-mode-hook (lambda  () (org-bullets-mode 1))))
                </div>
                <br>

            <p class="has-text-black">
                You may be wondering 'what's up with all the parentheses' and I think that's a fair observation, I belive the reason for the parentheses is because in all lisp languages everything is a list which is a very weird consept to get used to. In fact I'm not every really used to it yet to be honest. But I am learing more and more about elisp and I find it pretty intresting even though it is odd compared to something like C or Python or something.
                <br>
                <br>
                You can expect more from me about the topic of Emacs as I have a feeling that I'm really just getting started with understanding it.
                <br>
                <br>
                Thanks for reading :)
            </p>
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Contribute to FOSS</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/contribute-to-foss</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/contribute-to-foss</link>
<pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 12:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
<h1 class="subtitle">There are many ways</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                If you have been using FOSS for any amount of time you know one of the key things many of us love about FOSS is that we are able to help in the creation or fixing of issues with the software we use. But many people have no clue how to help, I'm here to help with that.
            </p>
            <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Contribute code</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    The most common thought for most people is you have to contribute code, this isn't true however if you have the skills to contribute code in the languages used by the program you are contributing to i'm sure the devs are more than happy to accept it assuming that you have clean and readable code.
                </p>
                <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Documentation</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    Documentation is maybe one of the most important parts of a program that is often over looked by developers, if you aren't fluent in code that's ok because you can right documentation for the projects you support. If they project is fairly large already there is a good chance it will already have good documentation but that doesn't mean you can help in this area, if you speak more than one language you can translate the documentation from is originally written language into the language you know. For example say a project has documentation written in Russian and you know Russian as well as German, you could translate it from Russian to German. The devs will be thankful and anyone using the program who speaks German would also be very thankful to have documentation in their native language.
                </p>
                <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Help the community</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    In the world of linux we often see people asking questions, rather it be new to linux users or experienced users everyone has to ask questions every now and again. If you have the skills and understanding of linux required to help you can answer questions of forums and other places online. It may seem like a trivial thing but it's very helpful to getting more people comfortable with their systems and in turn converting more people to more FOSS alternatives.
                </p>
                <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Create content</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    When people hear create content you may think that means make a Odysee or YouTube channel and yes that is a very good way because you could reach people who haven't heard of FOSS and they may give it a try after seeing your videos but also you could make art for the projects of your choice, such as logos, or icons for desktop environments or window manager, or even memes, yes memes are actually surprisingly helpful as memes are essentially modern day slang, you can give them a laugh while also spreading the message of FOSS.
                </p>
                <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Advocacy</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    Advocacy can be as simple as telling your friends and family about FOSS, you could also gather a following on social platforms and spead the message that way.
                </p>
                <br>
                <br>

                <h1 class="title is-4">Donation</h1>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                    Many free and open source projects are made and maintained in the devs free time for free, so if you have the extra cash every now and then send the devs a bit of money to show that you support and appreciate their work and commitment to the projects.
                </p>
                <br>
                <br>
                <p class="has-text-black">
                There are many ways to contribute to the FOSS community and projects, I encourage everyone to contribute in anyway they can.
                    <br>
                    <br>
                    Thank you for reading :)
                </p> 
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>I'm Back Again</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/im-back</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/im-back</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 05 Aug 2021 06:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">I have a job now, give me a break lol</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                Hello again, It's been a while. I'm mostly just making this blog to get myself back into the motion of writing a blog. See ya next time :)
                <br>
                p.s. I will try to start making posts simi-regularly again.
                </p> 
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Back to VIM</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/back-to-vim</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/back-to-vim</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2021 12:30:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Am I home now?</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                As anyone who has read any of my blog post would know I had a period of time where I was obsessed with Emacs, Doom Emacs to be more accurate.
                <br>
                <br>
                I did everything in Emacs from tooting on mastodon to looking through my directoies on my computer but recently that has changed, I have known about SpaceVIM for a while but I've decided to give it a try but not how you may think.
                <br>
                I will be using SpaceVIM with GVim for any who doesn't know GVim is the GUI version of VIM which is normally used at the commandline.
            </p>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
              I plan to give updates in my journy with GVim and SpaceVIM so stick around for that :)
              <br>
              <br>
              Thanks for reading :)
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>My job is killing me</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/work</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/work</link>
<pubDate>Thu, 09 Sept 2021 2:15:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
            <h1 class="subtitle">Moral is low buckos</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                I'm still young and haven't really worked that much in compared to many people, but one thing I do know is I cannot stand having someone dictating when I'm allowed to do things, if that makes me sound like a bratty kid than so be it.
                <br>
                I will be looking into other options to make a living, preferably something I can do from home, I'm not much of a people person and having to work with people all day seriously drains the life out of me as well and wears on my mental state.
                <br>
                If you have any ideas for work I could do from home I would be more than happy to hear suggestions.
                <br>
                <br>
                That's all I have to say, that's the post...
            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Learning to code</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/learing-code</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/learing-code</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sept 2021 5:55:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
             <h1 class="subtitle">I've made no progress but I'm still interested</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                I gained an intrest in coding and programming in highschool when I had a class for Web Design, The class only taught the most basic of basic HTML and CSS but it was enough to get me intrested.
                But after the class was over I didn't really go back to it for about a year, I had just graduated highschool (barely) when I started looking more into coding. I like web development a lot,
                However my skills have barely improved at all, I feel like I don't fully understand anything, It's like I understand things just enough to kinda sorta implement them.
            </p>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                This same issue carries over into programming as well,
                So for example Java was the first actual programming language I ever started to learn and I hated it because of how tedious it was to type,
                so I looked at python and I'm still in the same boat. Actually I've played around with nearly every language and I still seem to have the issue of not fully getting anything.
                <br>
                <br>
                Maybe I'm stupid or maybe the issue is just too much hopping between languages and not enough dedication to a language to fully understand anything I've tried to learn.
                <br>
                <br>
                I tried to make this one a little longer on purpose, I feel like so many of my recent-ish posts are just so short and pointless lol

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

<item>
<title>Speaking your mind</title>
<guid>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/speaking-your-mind</guid>
<link>https://koreymoffett.com/blog/speaking-your-mind</link>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Sept 2021 00:41:00 UTC</pubDate>
<description>
    <![CDATA[
             <h1 class="subtitle">I've made no progress but I'm still interested</h1>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                I gained an intrest in coding and programming in highschool when I had a class for Web Design, The class only taught the most basic of basic HTML and CSS but it was enough to get me intrested.
                But after the class was over I didn't really go back to it for about a year, I had just graduated highschool (barely) when I started looking more into coding. I like web development a lot,
                However my skills have barely improved at all, I feel like I don't fully understand anything, It's like I understand things just enough to kinda sorta implement them.
            </p>
            <br>
            <p class="has-text-black">
                This same issue carries over into programming as well,
                So for example Java was the first actual programming language I ever started to learn and I hated it because of how tedious it was to type,
                so I looked at python and I'm still in the same boat. Actually I've played around with nearly every language and I still seem to have the issue of not fully getting anything.
                <br>
                <br>
                Maybe I'm stupid or maybe the issue is just too much hopping between languages and not enough dedication to a language to fully understand anything I've tried to learn.
                <br>
                <br>
                I tried to make this one a little longer on purpose, I feel like so many of my recent-ish posts are just so short and pointless lol

            </p>
]]>
</description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss>
